autocarindia.com 2019-12-23

# 

This privacy policy has been compiled to serve users / subscribers who access or view the website at the domain name, [www.autocarindia.com](https://www.autocarindia.com/) (Website) that is owned and operated by Haymarket SAC Publishing (India) Private Limited (Haymarket). In this policy, use of the terms "we", "us" and "our" refers to Haymarket.

We respect your privacy and we are committed to protecting your Personal Information. We maintain consistently high levels of best practice in our processing of your Information and comply with all applicable laws.

This privacy policy governs the access, collection, usage, handling, storage and disclosure of your personal information during the course of your usage of the Website. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. This Policy is intended to assist you in making informed decisions about your Personal Information when using our website or the services provided by us or our group companies. Please take a few moments to read and understand the Policy.

Personal Information means any information that relates to a natural person, which, either directly or indirectly, in combination with other information available or likely to be available with a body corporate, is capable of identifying such person. This means that Personal Information can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual.

By accessing and using the Website and services, you accept the terms of, and be bound by this privacy policy; and consent to our collection, use, handling, storage and disclosure of your Personal Information as described in this privacy policy. This privacy policy may be updated from time to time and we will notify you of any changes to our privacy policy by posting the new privacy policy here. You are advised to consult this privacy policy regularly for any changes, as your continued access and use of the Website shall be deemed to be your approval and acceptance of all changes to this privacy policy.

In addition to this privacy policy, each service offered by us or our group companies may have additional privacy provisions that are specific to that particular service. These supplemental disclosures are made adjacent to the particular service at the time your Personal Information is collected. A list of our group companies can be seen at the end of this document.

**What personal information do we collect and how we use it?**

  * Subscriber provided information - We collect and maintain the Personal Information that you voluntarily enter through the online form published on our Website, when you accept the terms of use of the Website, subscribe to a newsletter, magazine, enter a competition, participate in social networking activities, participate in surveys, contact us for help, or otherwise enter information on the Website before or during its use. When entering information on the Website, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, demographic information, email address, mailing address, phone number, age, username, profile information on a social network (if you have signed up via a social network), or other details, for us to help you with your experience, to improve the Website, to contact you and respond to your information requests. We use this as appropriate for our business purposes, including administering your account (if any), registering and providing you access to the Website, responding to your queries, fulfilling your relevant requests, share relevant advertisements, to run competitions, contact you for future editions of conferences and symposiums, deliver services and other related and ancillary purposes. If you would like us to amend, delete this Personal Information provided by you or want us to provide you a copy of your Personal Information available with us, you may write to us at [hsac.cpo@haymarketsac.in](mailto:hsac.cpo@haymarketsac.in). You may also choose not to provide us with your Personal Information.
  * Other Information – We may also collect certain other information, such as device ID, device make/model, IP address, geographical location (when enabled), browser type, operating system, page views, website navigation, timing and frequency of use of the Website, marketing preferences, name of your wireless carrier, other data relating to malfunctions when you use the Website. We use this information purely for analytics and research purposes and to ensure the security of our website.
  * Cookies - Cookies are small files transferred to the hard drive of your device (if you allow) that enable us to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current activity on the Website, which allows us to improve the Content on the Website. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate and anonymized data about the traffic on the Website so that we can offer better experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third-party services that track this information on our behalf. Advertisers or other third parties using our website may also use cookies and other technologies for understanding user preferences. We do not control these advertisers or other parties' use of cookies or other technologies or what they do with the Personal Information they collect. You can limit the way that we tailor advertising based on your Personal Information by objecting to the cookies that we or third parties wish to place on your browser or deleting the cookies that we or third parties have placed on your browser.
  * Information received from third parties - We may also combine online and/or offline information received from third parties (including other members of our group of companies) with your Personal Information. Such Personal Information received from third parties is used for a variety of purposes including to verify other Personal Information about you (e.g., verify your mailing address to send you requested products or services) and to enhance the content and relevance of the advertising we provide to you.

**Marketing and Promotions**

  * We may send you marketing and promotional materials and information about our other products or services offered by Haymarket SAC Publishing (India) Private Limited and our group companies, where you have provided us with the appropriate consents.
  * Some or all of the Personal Information collected during a promotion, contest or poll may be disclosed publicly. It may also be shared with other third parties as disclosed and consented to by you at the time of collection or in the rules of such promotions, polls or contests. These third parties may include providers of prizes in order to update you of your status of your prize or other fulfilment needs or a co-sponsor who may use your Information to administer the promotional activity or for their marketing purposes, but only in conformance with your consent, or with the terms published at the time your personal data is collected. We are not responsible for the privacy policy or practices of third parties.

**Children**

Children under 16 - The Website is not designed for children; and we do not knowingly market to children. Parents and guardians are advised to supervise children while they are online. A parent or guardian may submit a request to [hsac.cpo@haymarketsac.in](mailto:hsac.cpo@haymarketsac.in) to stop any further use of the Personal Information received from a child or to request that we suppress such Personal Information, to the best of our ability. Before disclosing Personal Information about a child, we may request that the parent or guardian provide reasonable Information for identification purposes.

**Retention of your Personal Information**

  * Your personal information shall not be retained for longer than is necessary for the purposes for which we collect them, unless otherwise required for the purposes of fulfilling any legal obligation. During this period, as a user, you may also request us to delete this personal information. If you do not wish to share you personal information, please do not access or view our Website, as some of the personal information is collected automatically upon your visit to the Website.
  * You may instruct us not to process your Personal Information for marketing or other purposes and delete your information, if required. You may do so by writing to us at [hsac.cpo@haymarketsac.in](mailto:hsac.cpo@haymarketsac.in). 
  * You also have right to request us to update, amend, correct, complete or delete your Personal Information retained by us through email.

**How do we protect your information**

  * We take the safety of your Personal Information and its confidentiality very seriously and we provide reasonable security safeguards commensurate to the sensitivity of the personal information being handled and have implemented security practices including but not limited to physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect your information. We implement a variety of security measures when a user enters, submits, or accesses their information to maintain the safety of your Personal Information.
  * The Website is scanned on a regular basis for any known vulnerabilities in order to make your use as safe as possible.
  * Your Personal Information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.
  * Please be aware that, although we endeavor to provide reasonable security for your Personal Information, no security system can prevent all potential security breaches.
  * We endeavor to ensure to the best of our ability that all third party service providers whose services which we may use, maintain security standards that are equivalent to our security standards and commensurate with market practices, in the context of the sensitivity of your sensitive personal data or information being stored or handled.

**Disclosures to third parties**

  * We do not sell, trade, publish or otherwise transfer your Personal Information to outside parties, unless we provide you with advance notice and obtain your prior consent to do so.
  * This does not include our trusted service providers or group companies, including without limitation, our hosting partners, third party vendors (payment wallets, web designers etc.) and other parties who assist us in operating the Website, conducting our business, or serving our users so long as they agree to keep this information confidential, do not have any independent use of the information we disclose to them, and remain responsible for the protection of your Personal Information. You hereby give us your consent to transfer your Personal Information to such third parties as listed here.
  * Your Personal Information collected by us may be transferred to, stored and processed outside India; and may be accessed and processed by our group companies. By submitting Information to us, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all reasonable steps necessary to ensure that your Personal Information is treated securely in accordance with this privacy policy.
  * In addition, where you have provided us with the appropriate consents, we may also disclose your Personal Information for marketing purposes or host messages on behalf of one or more of our group companies or other selected trusted third parties in the following sectors where the Personal Information they provide will be relevant or of interest to you: Professional Associations, Automotive, Charity, Education and Training, Recruitment, Business and Leisure Travel, Events, Conferences and Exhibitions, Financial Services, Surveys and Research, Media, Broadcast and Marketing, Publishing and Subscriptions, Business and Information Services, Electronics, computers, Software and AV, Sports and Sportswear, Gaming, Betting, Telecoms and Retail and Partners and Sponsors of Promotions, Events and Competitions.
  * We may also release certain limited information when its release is required to comply with the law, enforce our policies, or protect ours or others' rights, property or safety, investigate fraud or respond to a government request.
  * We may, however, disclose aggregated user statistics or other information that is incapable of identifying any individual subscriber in order to describe, market or advertise our Website and Content to current and prospective business partners and to other third parties for other lawful purposes.

**Links to other websites**

The Website may include links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from ours. If you submit your personal information to any of those sites, your information will be governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to read the privacy statement of any website you visit as we do not monitor, control, or endorse the privacy practices of any third parties.

**Who is the Grievance Officer?**

If you wish to report a security breach, have a problem that you are unable to resolve or otherwise require any other assistance in respect of the Website and this privacy policy, you may contact our Grievance Officer whose details are provided below:

**Name** : Hital Vyas  
**E-mail** : [hsac.cpo@haymarketsac.in](mailto:hsac.cpo@haymarketsac.in)  
**Address** : Unit No. 401, 502 & 503, 4th/5th Floor, Raheja Xion, Opp. Nirmal Park, Dr. B. Ambedkar Marg, Byculla (E), Mumbai - 400027.  
**Telephone** : 022-23787511 

Haymarket is committed to the privacy, safety and security of our customers. If you discover a potential security vulnerability, we would appreciate it if you could report it to us in a responsible manner. We will respond to you as soon as possible. Publicly disclosing a potential vulnerability could put the wider community at risk, and therefore we encourage you to come to us first. We'll keep you informed as we move forward with our investigations.
